Abhishek Sharma

Date of Birth: 1st Nov' 98 Residence: Kolkata, WB

Data scientist with 2 years of experience & a **Masters in Applied AI** | I am passionate about using analytics & building models to generate value for stakeholders. I am comfortable working in an **agile environment** and across **multiple domains**.

Experience_

StatsPerform
AI APPRENTICE

Remote (company based in Chicago, Illinois)

September 2022-March 2023

- Started & developed the **AI monitoring project**, an automated generalised framework to periodically **calculate evaluation and performance metrics** for probabilistic model predictions, **flag anomalies**, and **analyse trends**, ultimately **saving developer time & company cost**.
- · Learned AWS based applications like Redshift, DynamoDB, Lambda, and SQS from scratch and built a functioning pipeline using the same.

360 Scouting BV

Remote (company based in Groningen, Netherlands)

June 2021-June 2022

DATA SCIENTIST (FREELANCE)

- Was part of a small data science/engineering team who were building a **machine learning model** to evaluate player actions using a contextual probabilistic approach, and creating ranked shortlists which were sold to a **Champions League** football club (one of the **most popular football clubs in Europe).**
- Created data visualisations in Python for internal stakeholders to analyze model performance across varying levels of granularity.

Total Football Analysis

Remote (company based in Berlare, Belgium)

January – August 2019

• Wrote weekly analyses - match reports, player & team profiles - for the website (full list of **18 publications** here) & monthly issues for their industry-leading magazine on 3 occasions.

Freelance Projects for Individual Clients

DATA ANALYST/CONSULTANT

- Worked with analysts from Villarreal CF (one of the biggest football clubs in the world) to prepare pre-match data reports for the first team manager, create dashboards for the academy coaches, & set up data infrastructures locally to ingest data from APIs.
- Created data visualizations & graphics (primarily in matplotlib) for three books <u>Chelsea: Europe's Next Powerhouse</u>, <u>Anatomy of a Genius</u>,
 & <u>Lionesses</u>: <u>Gamechangers</u>.

Skills _

ANALYST

Programming Python, R, Julia

Cloud AWS (RedShift, DynamoDB, Lambda)
Databases SQL (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB)

Relevant Frameworks Keras, Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Business Intelligence Tableau, MS Office suite

Other HTML/CSS/JS, Plotly, Git, Bash, Heroku

Coursework Algorithms, Data Structures, OOP, Probability & Discrete Mathematics,
Completed Data Science Statistics, Machine Learning, Time Series Analysis, A/B Testing

*emboldened indicate skills with more experience

Education_

Vijaybhoomi University

Techno India University

Karjat, Maharashtra

M.S. in Data Science & Artificial Intelligence

Sep 2020 – Sep 2022

8.13 CGPA \ First in class

BBA (Hons.)

Kolkata, West Bengal Aug 2017 – Aug 2020

Projects.

Futbolista.jl

AUTHOR | JULIA PACKAGE

- Allows to load various public datasets, create typical visualizations, & interface with advanced models for tracking data.
- Installable from the Julia package manager.

xGPlayground

CO-CREATOR | WEB APPLICATION, CONVOLUTIONAL NEURAL NETWORK EXPECTED GOALS MODEL

- Allows users to set up shooting situations & dynamically makes predictions.
- Model served via **Tensorflow.js** & site built using vanilla HTML/CSS/JavaScript.